Inventory of the Andrew Denny Rodgers papers, 1893-1959
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Andrew Denny Rodgers papers
1893-1959
Rodgers, Andrew Denny, 1900-1981
01935
5.78 cubic ft. (13 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Contains materials compiled by Andrew Denny Rodgers in his research of Indian irrigation in the U.S. and Federal reclamation projects.
Biography of Andrew Denny Rodgers
Andrew Denny Rodgers, III (1900-1981) was born in Columbus, Ohio and graduated from Ohio Wesleyan University in 1922, followed by law school at Ohio State University in 1925. He practiced law from 1926-1933 and later became a historian of botany and botanists.
Scope and Content
Collection contains materials relating to Rodgers's interest in land use and reclamation, including 158 interviews and research notes with engineers and other individuals involved with irrigation and water resources development in the west, 1904-1957; research notes on the Indian Irrigation Service and irrigation projects on Indian reservations containing newspaper clippings, maps and correspondence, 1914-1960; manuscripts for "Federal Reclamation's Pioneer Period: A Biographical Study of its Origins, Organization, and Early Work of its Engineer Corps" and "Indian Irrigation: Its Organization and Techniques"; and a scrapbook with photographs, newspaper clippings and biographical information on John Lucian Savage (1879-1967), a civil engineer for the U.S. Bureau of Reclamation, 1953.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are several other known archival collections created by Andrew Denny Rodgers. The Library of Congress and the Ohio Historical Society hold collections of Rodgers's papers and the Farlow Reference Library at Harvard University has approximately a folder of his materials.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from Andrew Denny Rodgers in 1966.
Access Terms
Savage, John Lucian, 1879-1967; United States. Bureau of Reclamation.; United States. Indian Irrigation Service.; Irrigation -- West (U.S.); Water resources development -- West (U.S.); Indians of North America -- Agriculture.; West (U.S.) -- History.; Maps.; Manuscripts.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Historians.; Authors, American.; Rodgers, Andrew Denny, 1900-1981: Federal reclamation's pioneer period; Rodgers, Andrew Denny, 1900-1981: Indian Irrigation
Agriculture and Natural Resources; Water and Water Rights; Native Americans; Politics, Government, and Law
Container List
- Container list
  - Interviews and research notes, circa 1914-1957 (Box 1)
  - Indian Irrigation Book - research notes, circa 1911-1959 (Box 2)
  - Navajo Project, New Mexico - Supplemental Report to Feasibility Report, 1957 March (Box 2)
  - Photograph: Andrew D. Rodgers, undated (Box 2)
  - Indian Irrigation Book - research notes, circa 1909-1959 (Box 3)
  - Notebook/scrapbook - Federal Reclamation, circa 1918-1959 (Box 4)
  - Notebook: Indian Affairs - Reclamation, undated (Box 4)
  - Research notes - irrigation - Federal Reclamation - reservations, circa 1911-1958 (Box 4)
  - Biographical material, circa 1953 (Box 5)
  - Research notes on Federal Reclamation, circa 1910-1959 (Box 5)
  - Research notes - scrapbook - irrigation on reservations, circa 1919-1959 (Box 6)
  - Summary of Irrigation Data of various projects. U.S. Indian Irrigation Service, 1924, 1924, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Research notes from (formerly) bound scrapbook - Indian irrigation, circa 1906-1957 (Box 7)
  - Research notes from (formerly) bound scrapbook - irrigation, circa 1902-1954 (Box 8)
  - Research notes from (formerly) bound scrapbook - irrigation and reclamation projects, circa 1893-1956 (Box 9)
  - Research notes from (formerly) bound scrapbook - Federal Reclamation projects, circa 1904-1956 (Box 10)
  - Manuscript: "Federal Reclamation's Pioneer Period,", circa 1958 (Box 11)
  - Manuscript: "Indian Irrigation, its organization and achievements,", undated (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook - John Lucian Savage, 1902-1957 (Box 13)